writertown.com 2011-01-06

# Verio Privacy Policy

In the course of serving its customers, Verio acquires, stores and transmits customer communications and information that customers may regard as private or sensitive. Some of this information - such as the customer’s name, address, telephone number, and credit card data - is provided to Verio by its customers in order to establish service. Other information - such as the customer’s account status, choice of services, and customer logs - is created and maintained by Verio in the normal course of providing service. Verio also uses cookies, which are small pieces of information that a web site can store in a designated file on a user’s computer for various reasons. For example, Verio uses cookies on the landing pages of products sold online which record the customer information that is required on the order form. This information is then forwarded to an internal sales tracking database within Verio. In addition, Verio may store customers’ electronic mail and other communications as a necessary incident to the transmission and delivery of those communications. 

This Privacy Policy applies only to Verio’s treatment of data collected online, and does not apply to any offline data collection practices or to the data collection practices of any third parties, Verio customers, or any entities affiliated with Verio. Also, please note that use of Verio’s website constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy. 

Verio’s policies and procedures for handling customer information have been created with the understanding that Internet technologies are still evolving and that Internet business methods are continuing to evolve to meet the needs and opportunities of the changing technologies. As a result, Verio’s policies and procedures are subject to change. Changes will be posted to the website and use of Verio's website will constitute acceptance of and agreement to be bound by those changes. 

Data Security

Verio protects the confidentiality of its customers’ information, account information and personal communications. To secure the information collected online, prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure only appropriate use of information that is collected from customers, Verio has implemented appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. Further, Verio requires that employees keep customer information confidential. Verio cautions its customers and website visitors that no medium of communication, including the Internet, is entirely secure. Accordingly, Verio cannot be responsible for loss, corruption or unauthorized acquisition and use of personal information provided to our website, or for any damages resulting from such loss, corruption, unauthorized acquisition or unauthorized use. 

How is customer information used?

Verio may share customer information with selected partners, for example, to provide customers with information about products which might be of interest to the customer or to enable the customer to take advantage of special partner programs. Verio may also use customer information to provide its customers with system information or information about new or upgraded products. In addition, Verio may collect and share non personally identifiable information (such as website usage information) from visitors to its web sites with third-party companies for various purposes such as statistical analysis, performance optimization and promotional uses. In the case of a business transaction, including but not limited to, a merger or sale of a portion of Verio’s assets, customer information will likely be part of the assets transferred. In this event, Verio will attempt to notify impacted customers that their information has been transferred. 

Opt Out & Modifications

Customers may opt out of receiving notices of new or upgraded products from Verio and Verio partners by filling out this on-line No Solicitation Request form. However, customers may not opt out of receiving information from Verio that is essential for maintaining or updating customers’ accounts or system information. 

Most customers may access and modify their personal information via their online personal control panel/account information page. All other customers may access and modify their personal information by contacting the appropriate Verio Billing organization. 

Domain name customers who have registered a domain name with Verio and wish to change the Technical Contact from Verio to another company, may send a request to [veriohostmaster@verio.net](mailto:veriohostmaster@verio.net). It is important to note that customer domain name registration information is made publicly available in the registry of domain names. 

Disclosure of customer information and communications

Verio will not otherwise disclose its customers’ personal and account information unless Verio has reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to identify, make contact with, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing harm or interfering with the rights or property of Verio, Verio’s customers, or others, or where Verio has a good faith belief that the law requires such disclosure such as in response to legal process seeking disclosure of such information. 

Verio also will not, except for reasons stated below, disclose to third parties the contents of any electronic mail or other electronic communications that Verio stores or transmits for its customers. The circumstances under which Verio will disclose such electronic customer communications are when: 

  1. it is necessary in order to provide service to the customer; 
  2. it is necessary to protect the legitimate interests of Verio and its customers; 
  3. it is required to cooperate with interception orders, warrants, or other legal process that Verio determines in its sole discretion to be valid and enforceable; and 
  4. it is necessary to provide to a law enforcement agency when the contents are inadvertently obtained by Verio and appear to pertain to the commission of a crime. 

Verio disclaims any intention to censor, edit or engage in ongoing review or surveillance of communications stored on or transmitted through its facilities by customers or others. Verio, however, review, delete or block access to communications that may harm Verio, its customers or third parties. The grounds on which Verio may take such action include, but are not limited to, actual or potential violations of Verio’s Acceptable Use Policy.
